<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Ryan Irelan</title>
    <description>Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/ryan&quot;&gt;@ryan on Micro.blog&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 17:08:54 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 17:08:54 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Took nighttime cold medicine last night and then stayed awake to see what it felt like when it kicked in. Don’t do that! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 16:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/25/took-nighttime-cold.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/25/took-nighttime-cold.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My marathon training site ryanruns.com is archived at the domain. This account is general purpose until my next adventure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/manton&quot;&gt;@manton&lt;/a&gt; for making it easy to move my site/content out to Github as a permanent static archive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 14:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/22/my-marathon-training.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/22/my-marathon-training.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Marathon Wrap-up</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am wrapping up this version of my microblog with a recap of the culmination of months of training: completing my first marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-weather&quot;&gt;The Weather&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overcast but warm. Much warmer than I had anticipated. I showed up at the start in a light racing jacket so I stayed warm but really didn’t need it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Last year it poured for 5 miles of my half marathon. I was soaked &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; cold because of colder temperatures. This year it poured for a couple of miles but it was humid and warm (6os).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It got much warmer as the morning went on. The sun came out, which wasn’t in the forecast.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I trained in Austin, Texas Summer and Fall weather. I’m very accustomed to the heat and running in it. But I let my guard down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-did-wrong&quot;&gt;What I Did Wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I didn’t hydrate enough in the first 12 miles of the race. I met up with my wife and daughter around mid-race and realized my water bottle was still too full and my Gatorade Endurance bottle was also too full. I should’ve completely depleted both by mile 12.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I trusted the weather forecast and didn’t change plans once on the course. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I became dehydrated mid-race and at mile 14 my calf muscles started cramping. I went from running to that weird hoppity hop like I was stepping on hot coals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I didn’t rehydrate fast enough (I don’t know if I could), which meant more walking than I really should’ve done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-did-right&quot;&gt;What I Did Right&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started the race slow and easy. I didn’t worry too much about whether I could finish (barring injury or illness) because I would bring it home even if I had to fight hard (Narrator: And, oh, how he did).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No lost toenails, no foot issues, no blisters, no chafing. My work on properly lubing and using only gear I was experienced with really paid off. I had a rough day but it could’ve been worse with these completely preventable issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I trained with the course drink (Gatorade Endurance) because I wanted to be prepared to have to consume it without any worry about stomach problems. This turned out to be a really, really smart move.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I carried two soft Ultimate Direction water bottles. One had water, one had the Gatorade Endurance. The plan was to fill up the Gatorade one at every available aid station and hand off the water one after the first half marathon when I saw my support team (my wife and daughter).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I also trained using the same gels for almost the entirety of my training schedule. This also meant I could down gels without worrying about stomach issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I kept a cool head when things started to go wrong. Once I hydrated more my thoughts became even more lucid and rational. I attribute this to having hit rough spots during my training and knowing that hydration is the linchpin of this entire thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m proud of my overall performance because I met my goal of finishing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m proud that I kept cool under enormous personal pressure. I’ve trained for this race since August, thought about it since winter, and it became a huge goal for me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I met a group of guys who all worked together to finish the race. I’m very insular and a loner when it comes to running. This was a nice change (even if it was mostly out of necessity).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will a run a marathon again?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. I want to improve in the areas where I messed up. I’ll be back at it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 20:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/21/marathon-wrapup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/22/marathon-wrapup.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Had a race report written but app crashed and lost it all. Will try again later this week. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 08:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/04/had-a-race.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/04/had-a-race.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I mismanaged the first 12 miles of fluid intake and it caught up with me. The weather was warmer than expected and I lost track of my hydration. Around mile 14 I had cramping and slowed down to focus on getting as much salty fluids (Gatorade Endurance) in me. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 15:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/03/i-mismanaged-the.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/03/i-mismanaged-the.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Marathon complete! Took longer than planned because of calf cramping. But I crossed that frickin finish line. 👍🏃🏼‍♂️🍺&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 15:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/03/marathon-complete-took.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/03/marathon-complete-took.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Checked into the hotel. Heading over to get my bib. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 14:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/02/checked-into-the.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/02/checked-into-the.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I will run in the Saucony Guide ISOs on Sunday. Much of my training was done in Mizunos, which ended up injuring me. Switched back to Saucony in late October. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/95d6f73a16.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 08:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/01/i-will-run.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/01/i-will-run.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;2 days until the race. Start time is 7:15am on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 08:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/01/days-until-the.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/01/days-until-the.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First marathon stress dream: was running late for the start, my shoes were knee high and I couldn’t lace them. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 08:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/01/first-marathon-stress.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/12/01/first-marathon-stress.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last training run today. Now to focus on more rest, perhaps a bit of carbo-loading, and getting my head straight. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 08:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/29/last-training-run.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/29/last-training-run.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Making my playlist for Sunday. For a while I didn’t run with headphones but enjoying it again. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/27/making-my-playlist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/27/making-my-playlist.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 miles&lt;/strong&gt; which is part of the taper, I guess? Legs feel great and it was almost exactly the weather forecasted for next weekend’s marathon. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 19:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/25/miles-which-is.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/26/miles-which-is.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thankful. 🏃🏼‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/92aa3a9863.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 18:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/23/thankful.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/24/thankful.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 miles&lt;/strong&gt; this morning to keep active in the lead up to the marathon. I’m technically in my taper but my leg issue threw off my training plan. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 23:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/22/miles-this-morning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/23/miles-this-morning.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 miles&lt;/strong&gt; to test my legs. Feeling springy and good. A little soreness. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 09:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/18/miles-to-test.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/18/miles-to-test.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been resting my legs for the last week+. Whatever I did has lingered but my legs do feel better. At this point my training plan is out the window and I need to rethink it. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 08:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/04/ive-been-resting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/11/04/ive-been-resting.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My leg issues are persisting. After an easy 3 mile run on Thursday, my legs felt like I ran 5x that. It was more than soreness and stiffness. It was actual pain in both legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been pushing through some discomfort but it shouldn’t feel like this. It’s affecting my gait when I walk and for the first few miles of my runs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to rest. I don’t know anything beyond that at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 08:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/28/my-leg-issues.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/28/my-leg-issues.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just shy of &lt;strong&gt;11 miles&lt;/strong&gt; in beautiful, chilly, and rainy Portland, OR. I’m in town for work (teaching tomorrow). I ran along the waterfront, which was a nice change. No photos because I forgot my GoPro  and don’t carry my iPhone anymore now that I have a Series 3 Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 15:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/21/just-shy-of.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/21/just-shy-of.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Considering ordering a pair of the Saucony Guide 10s (my current pair are the 9s) to replace the Mizunos. I’m not really into collecting shoes but I need to kick the Mizunos to the curb. They don’t work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/8410083563.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;403&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 11:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/18/considering-ordering-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/18/considering-ordering-a.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 miles&lt;/strong&gt; in a glorious 49F. Switched back to my Sauconys after a couple of months running in the Mizunos. It’s notable how lightweight the Sauconys are. I did this because I suspect the shoes are causing some of my leg issues. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/7d05e2a879.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 07:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/18/miles-in-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/18/miles-in-a.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 miles&lt;/strong&gt; of a planned 16. I’m extremely disappointed I wasn’t able to complete the full run. I’ve been dealing with hamstring pain in my left leg and today it flared up at mile 5 and started radiating up to my lower back and down to my heel. More soon. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 08:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/14/miles-of-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/14/miles-of-a.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>3 Hour Run with Series 3 Nike+ Apple Watch (with LTE)</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday’s long run was my first run with the Apple Watch Series 3 GPS + LTE, Nike+ edition. I’ve been running with my Series 0 Apple Watch since 2015 but I always carried my phone with me. I have a giant iPhone 6s Plus and it’s annoying to carry, even using the SPIBelt. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous watches were a step better with built-in GPS but sometimes I am gone running for 1-3 hours at a time and I like to be able to get in touch with family if I need help. Up until Thursday, when Apple released the Series 3 Nike+ version, I would always need to carry my phone so I had a way to contact someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the GPS + LTE option on the Series 3 watches, I can finally ditch my phone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My run yesterday took 3 hours total and during that time I had the following enabled or turned on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LTE&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Workout app running (tracking my run)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heart rate sensor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bluetooth enabled with headphones connected&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music playing (saved to device)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, all of the default settings. I &lt;em&gt;did not&lt;/em&gt; have the Workout Power Saving Mode enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I glanced at my watch every mile or two, let’s say. Not too often. The screen was mostly unused over the three hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result? At the end of my run I had 33% battery remaining. Not perfect but still pretty good considering what the watch is doing during that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If I was a sub-3 marathoner (not even close) this might be enough. But I’m not, and it’s not.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my runs that go longer than 3 hours I’ll likely use the Workout Power Saving Mode, which turns off the celluar connection and heart rate sensor. No one will be able to reach &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; but I will be able to easily enable LTE and call or text someone if I need help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/1ae633b1c4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 09:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/08/hour-run-with.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/08/hour-run-with.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15 miles&lt;/strong&gt; for the long run today. This marks my longest run ever (previously 13.1), which is a major accomplishment for me but still not the ultimate goal. Today’s run started in the dark with a headlamp and ended with sunglasses in the sunshine. Also: ouch. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 09:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/07/miles-for-the.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/07/miles-for-the.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 miles&lt;/strong&gt; this morning out of a planned 7 miles. I’ve been dealing with sore legs (beyond normal soreness) and a slightly aggravated left hamstring. I’m trying to keep building miles while staying healthy. Tomorrow I’ll do 3 more miles to get my 7 and keep moving up in miles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 10:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/04/miles-this-morning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/04/miles-this-morning.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My new Apple Watch Nike edition shipped and should be here on Thursday. I’m looking forward to trying out the new cellular capability on my weekend long run. I hope I’ll never have to take my phone again. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 07:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/03/my-new-apple.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/03/my-new-apple.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 miles&lt;/strong&gt; this morning. The first run of the week is always a little rough in the beginning as I get loose again. We are back to warmer temps in the morning. It’s fine for 3 miles but tomorrow is 8. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/03/miles-this-morning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/10/03/miles-this-morning.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 miles&lt;/strong&gt; today in a step-back for the long run. I ran after sunrise but it was in the 60s so it felt good. When it’s cooler I definitely drink more water than Gatorade Endurance. It’s Fall but Austin still plans to bring the heat next week. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 13:46:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/30/miles-today-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/30/miles-today-in.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Took an extra rest day today. My legs need a slight reprieve. Going to stretch and talk nice to them over the next couple days. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 09:07:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/28/took-an-extra.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/28/took-an-extra.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 miles&lt;/strong&gt; this morning at a slightly faster pace. Trying to test my legs a bit. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 21:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/26/miles-this-morning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/27/miles-this-morning.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Using Workout App Instead of Strava</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was my first run using the built-in Apple Workout app on my Apple Watch. For more than a year I’ve used Strava on my phone and watch. I switched for two reasons: the Strava app is buggy, and the Workout app gives you stop/pause access via the Digital Crown and the other button (whatever it’s called). If you’ve ever tried to use your Apple Watch with wet or sweaty hands than you know why this matters. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 16:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/23/using-workout-app.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/23/using-workout-app.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13.1 miles&lt;/strong&gt; or exactly a half marathon for this week’s long run. I guess that means I’m almost halfway through my training. I got a later start (8am) so th temps weren’t on my side. This made for a tougher run and one time where I had to pull back because I was overheated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/89736a4971.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 10:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/23/miles-or-exactly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/23/miles-or-exactly.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is a (much needed) rest day. My only planned physical activity is my daily walk to my office. Strava shows 12 miles for the week, with another 13 planned for tomorrow’s long run. That’d be my biggest total miles logged in a single week. My legs definitely feel it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 06:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/22/today-is-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/22/today-is-a.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 miles&lt;/strong&gt; this morning. Still warm mornings, still tired legs. I’ve been listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audible.com/pd?asin=B01D24NLWO&amp;amp;source_code=ASSORAP0511160006&quot;&gt;Algorithms to Live By&lt;/a&gt; on my runs this past week. Good book so far. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 06:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/21/miles-this-morning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/21/miles-this-morning.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Honey Stinger Fruit Smoothie Gels</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordered a 24 count box of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/2017/09/02/miles-this-morning.html&quot;&gt;Honey Stinger Fruit Smoothie gels I tried a couple weeks ago&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon had the best price per ounce so I went with them. These gels don’t have caffeine so they’ll be my main fuel with caffeinated ones as a follow up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 08:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/20/honey-stinger-fruit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/20/honey-stinger-fruit.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m feeling the wear on my legs. Just generally tired and aching. As I get close the halfway point of the training schedule, I think my legs are hitting normal capacity and now working to get stronger. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 06:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/20/im-feeling-the.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/20/im-feeling-the.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 miles&lt;/strong&gt; this morning for the longer of my 3 weekday runs. I got an earlier start (shortly before 6) than usual because I was awake anyway. It’s hot again here in Austin. At 6 AM the temperature was 77 degrees. That makes for a tough run, even in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 06:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/20/miles-this-morning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/20/miles-this-morning.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 miles&lt;/strong&gt; today in the warm, humid morning air. Some extra stretching afterward because my legs are really starting to feel the miles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 06:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/19/miles-today-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/19/miles-today-in.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A popular anti-chafe salve in the trail running community is &lt;a href=&quot;[squirrels](http://squirrels) it utter.com&quot;&gt;Squirrel’s Nut Butter&lt;/a&gt;. That’s how I found out about it. I picked up a tin to try for long runs. It’s greasy, unlike Body Glide, but does a nice job on spots that Body Glide doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/eff3b0f400.jpg&quot; width=&quot;599&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 12:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/16/a-popular-antichafe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/16/a-popular-antichafe.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 miles&lt;/strong&gt; for the long run today. I saw that that temps were not going to get very low so I decided to get up early (for a weekend) and start at 6 AM. Running in the dark but cloud cover after sunrise meant the 75 degree temp was tolerable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 10:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/16/miles-for-the.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/16/miles-for-the.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another photo from my morning run in Cedar Rapids. I wonder what they make there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/92b39b8bec.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 11:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/13/another-photo-from.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/13/another-photo-from.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 miles&lt;/strong&gt; today in Cedar Rapids, Iowa. I ran on the Cedar River trail in the early morning sun and fog. Really nice run. Despite temps in the 50s I managed to work up a sweat. I was supposed to run 6 today but traveling required me to alter that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/ed9cb8f3b0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 10:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/13/miles-today-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/13/miles-today-in.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is a cross training day. I’ve never been very good about cross training days in the past (unless a nap counts) but today I did a couple miles hike at Wild Basin Nature Reserve with my family. Not too strenuous or long but just enough to loosen up my legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/0bf4decffb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 12:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/10/today-is-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/10/today-is-a.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7 mile&lt;/strong&gt; long run today. It’s a step-back week so nothing too challenging but next weekend is back at the higher mileage. High 60s and breezy this morning. Got out late so I had to deal with sun being higher in the sky. Good thing I was sporting my new pair of Goodr sunglasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/e10141fdf1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 09:22:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/09/mile-long-run.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/09/mile-long-run.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 miles&lt;/strong&gt; on really nice 59 degree morning. First cool morning run here in Austin since early Spring. I have a little discomfort in my left hamstring so I’m going to rest up before my Saturday long run. This week is a step back week in my training plan; my long run is only 7 miles. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/ede86e43c5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 06:41:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/07/miles-on-really.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/07/miles-on-really.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 miles&lt;/strong&gt; today, as per my training plan. It’s hard to get motivated for 5 miles at 6 AM in the dark. But this is a goal that requires completing each small step along the way. One thing that helps me get out the door at 6 AM is to set out my gear the night before. I fill up my bottle, set out my shoes, shorts, shirt, socks, hat, headlamp (it’s really dark in some spots), and headphones. I have a system for getting geared up and go through the motions and then I’m out the back door a few minutes later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 12:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/06/miles-today-as.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/06/miles-today-as.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 miles&lt;/strong&gt; today. My first run since Saturday’s long run. The start was a little clunky as I got my legs but felt good about a mile in. I pushed the pace a little to see how it felt. Not bad!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 06:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/05/miles-today-my.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/05/miles-today-my.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;And the Strava app on my Apple Watch crapped out at mile 8, missing two miles of running. This is probably why most runners use a dedicated watch, not a Apple Watch. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 09:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/02/and-the-strava.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/02/and-the-strava.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 miles&lt;/strong&gt; this morning for my scheduled long run. I got out much later (8am) than planned because I watched the live stream of the first group of finishers at UTMB. The temperature was higher than ideal so part of the run was a slog. Tried a new gel today: the Honey Stinger Fruit Smoothie was pretty good and sat well in my stomach. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/06019959b0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 09:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/02/miles-this-morning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/02/miles-this-morning.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is a rest day according to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/training-plan&quot;&gt;training plan&lt;/a&gt;. No running for me today but I am watching the &lt;a href=&quot;http://utmbmontblanc.com&quot;&gt;UTMB race coverage&lt;/a&gt; while working in my studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ryanruns.com/uploads/2017/5487b09606.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 12:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/01/today-is-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ryan.micro.blog/2017/09/01/today-is-a.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
